ronharris.com 2013-05-23

# Privacy Policy

**Ronharris.com Privacy Policy**

**Last Modified Date** : 2/11/13 

This Privacy Policy applies to the following Web site: 

("Site" or "we/our") 

**1\. We are totally committed to protecting your privacy and security.** The following information is designed to help you understand how we collect, use, disseminate and safeguard the information you provide to us while accessing and using our Site. By accessing and using our Site, you signify your assent to this Privacy Policy. If you do not agree with our information practices, please do not access or use our Site. As provided below, we reserve the right, at our discretion, to change, add or remove portions of this policy at any time by posting such changes to this page. Such changes will be effective upon posting. The Site requests that you read this Privacy Policy carefully and consult it regularly. 

**2\. Types of Information Collected and Uses of Collected Information**

We will be collecting two different types of information about the Website Members of our Site: That being Personally Identifiable Information and Non-personally Identifiable Information. 

**Personally Identifiable Information** is information that identifies a particular Member. This information could be collected at different points throughout the site. It is optional for you to engage in any action or activity located on the site. If you choose to engage in the activities located on the site we may ask you to provide us with certain personal information about yourself, such as your first and last name, mailing address (including zip code), email address, telephone number and date of birth. An example would be when you fill out a profile on the site. If and when you order tokens, we may also ask you to provide the processor with your credit card number, expiration date and authentication codes or related information. Some of the information we ask you to provide will be identified as mandatory and some will be identified as voluntary. If you do not provide the mandatory information for a particular action that requires it, you will not be permitted to engage in that activity. Additionally, we collect any information that you voluntarily enter, including Personal Information, into any postings, comments, or forums within the RonHarris.com community. 

We use Personally Identifiable Information to provide products and services to you, administer sweepstakes and contests, enhance the operation of the Website, improve our marketing and promotional efforts, analyze Website use, improve our product and service offerings, and to tailor your experience with third parties as provided in Item 3 of this Privacy Policy. In addition, if you use our Website to send information to another person, we may store your personal information. We may also use Personally Identifiable Information to troubleshoot, resolve disputes, accomplish administrative tasks, contact you, enforce our agreements with you, including our Website Terms of Use and this Privacy Policy, comply with applicable law, and cooperate with law enforcement activities. 

**Non-Personally Identifiable Information** is information that does not identify a specific Member. This type of information may include, but is not limited to, things like the Uniform Resource Locator ("URL") of the website you visited before coming to our Website, the URL of the website you visit after leaving our Website, the type of browser you are using and your Internet Protocol ("IP") address. We, and/or our authorized Third Party Service Providers and Advertisers, may automatically collect this information when you visit our Website through the use of electronic tools like Cookies as described in Items 4 and 8 of this Privacy Policy. 

We use Non-Personally Identifiable Information to troubleshoot, administer the Website, analyze trends, gather demographic information, comply with applicable law, and cooperate with law enforcement activities. We may also share this information with our authorized Third Party Service Providers and Advertisers to measure the overall effectiveness of our online advertising, content, and programming. 

**3\. How Do We Share Personal Information**

We will not share, sell, rent, or trade your Personally Identifiable Information with other parties except as provided below: 

In addition to any other information sharing or disclosure practices described in this Privacy Policy, we may share your Personal Information with third party service providers who perform some of our business functions on our behalf. These functions include, without limitation, sending administrative and promotional emails, and order processing and fulfillment. For example, we may disclose your billing information to payment processors to process fee payments or other financial transactions, or we may disclose your email address to email fulfillment contractors to send you emails from us. The use of your Personally Identifiable Information by such parties is governed by the privacy policies of such parties and is not subject to our control. 

We may share some or all of your Personal Information with our subsidiaries, joint venturers, or other companies under a common control (collectively, "affiliates"), in which case we will require these affiliates to honor this Privacy Policy. 

As with any other business, we could merge with, or be acquired by another company. If this occurs, the successor company would acquire the information we maintain, including Personally Identifiable Information. However, Personally Identifiable Information would remain subject to this Privacy Policy. 

We reserve the right to disclose your personally identifiable information as required by law and when we believe that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights and/or comply with a judicial proceeding, court order, or legal process served on our Website; enforce or apply this Privacy Policy, our Website Terms of Use or other agreements; or protect the rights, property or safety of the Website, its Members or others. 

**4\. How Do We Share Non-Personal Information**

We may disclose or share Non-Personal Information with certain business partners including, but not limited to, individuals and companies with whom we have business relationships, Merchants, and third party advertising companies with whom we have a business relationship. We may share aggregated demographic information (which does not include any Personal Information) with Advertisers. 

Additionally, we may use Third Party Service Providers to track and analyze Non-Personally Identifiable usage and volume statistics in order to administer and improve our Website. These statistics may also be used for promotional purposes, or to provide a representative audience for Advertisers. This information provides only general summaries of End User activities, and it does not include Personal Information. 

**5\. Updating and Correcting Information**

We believe that you should have the ability to access and edit the personal identifiable information that you provide us. if your information changes please log into your account and make the necessary corrections. You may also do this by e mailing 

_support@Ronharris.com_

. Please include your name, e mail address, password, and what information you would like changed when you contact us. 

We encourage you to promptly update your Personally Identifiable Information if it changes. You may ask to have the information on your account deleted or removed; however, because we keep track of past transactions, you cannot delete information associated with past transactions on the Website. 

**6.** **Members Choices on Collection and Use of Information**

As a condition of registration and the use of our products and services, we will send you Administrative and Promotional emails. 

**Administrative E mails:** We will send you information regarding your account activity and purchases as well as updates about our products and promotional offers. You cannot opt-out of Administrative Emails. "Administrative Emails" relate to a Member's activity on the Website, and include emails regarding a particular Member's account, requests or inquiries, and purchases of products and services. 

**Promotional E mails:** Promotional Emails advertise our products and services, including exclusive sales and other offers, and/or the products and services of our Advertisers and Affiliates. If you do not want to receive Promotional Emails from us, you may elect to opt-out of receiving Promotional Emails at any time after registering by e-mailing us at support@RonHarris.com, by writing to us at the address contained herein, or by hitting the "unsubscribe" button at the bottom of any of our e-mails. When contacting us, please indicate your name, address, email address, and what Promotional Emails you do not want to receive. 

**7\. Security**

We take information security seriously and take reasonable precautions to protect your Personal Information from unauthorized access and/or use, loss, disclosure, or alteration. Your password and email address are required for you to access your Personal Information on our Website. We recommend that you do not share your password with others. In addition access to this server is limited to select personnel and contractors.. 

Nonetheless, no data transmission over the Internet or any wireless network can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. As a result, while we employ commercially reasonable security measures to protect data and seek to partner with companies which do the same, there are security and privacy limitations of the Internet which are beyond our control. We cannot absolutely guarantee the security, integrity, and privacy of any and all information exchanged between you and us through the Website. We make no warranty, express, implied, or otherwise, that we will prevent unauthorized access to your private information and are not responsible for the actions of any third parties that may receive such information. 

**8\. Data Tracking Devices**

**Cookies** : This Website stores cookies on your computer in order to improve your RonHarris.com experience. Cookies are small text files stored by your browser on your computer's hard drive used to record a Member's preferences and session information. We use cookies to remind us who you are and track your interests so that we can provide you with a more customized experience. We may also use cookies to collect Non-Personal Information (such as the links you clicked on and other pages you visited) in order to improve our service. 

Advertisers may display advertisements on the Website, and these companies may place separate cookies on your computer. We have no control over these cookies, and such cookies are not covered by this Privacy Policy. Most browsers automatically accept cookies, but you may change your browser settings to limit which cookies you accept or to disable cookies altogether. If you decline or delete RonHarris.com cookies, some parts of the Website may not work properly. 

**9\. Privacy Policies of Third Party Websites**

This Privacy Policy only addresses the use and disclosure of information we collect from you on www.RonHarris.com. Other websites that may be accessible through this Website have their own privacy policies and data collection, use and disclosure practices. If you link to any such website, we urge you review the website's privacy policy. We are not responsible for the policies or practices of third parties. 

**10\. Other Privacy Issue**

**Children** : Members of the website must be above the age of 18. Individuals under the age of 18 may not use the website in any capacity. We do not knowingly collect personal information from anyone under the age of 18, and no part of the Website is designed to attract anyone under the age of 18. If you become aware that your child has provided us with Personal Information without your consent, please contact _support@Ronharris.com_. . If we become aware that a minor child has provided us with Personal Information without parental consent, we take steps to remove such information and terminate the minor's account. We do not collect or maintain information from anyone known to be under the age of legal capacity. ****

**Public Areas:** We may provide areas on our Website where you can publicly post information about yourself, can communicate with others such as discussion boards or blogs. This information may be accessible by other consumers and companies and may appear on other websites or web searches, and therefore this information could be read, collected, and used by others. We have no control over who reads your postings or what other Members may do with the information you voluntarily post, so please use caution when posting any personal information. ****

**11\. Notice of Privacy Rights to California Residents** . California law requires that we provide you with a summary of your privacy rights under the California Online Privacy Protection Act (the "Act") and the California Business and Professions Code. As required by the Act, we will provide you with the categories of Personally Identifiable Information that we collect through the Website and the categories of third party persons or entities with whom such Personally Identifiable Information may be shared for direct marketing purposes at your request. California law requires us to inform you, at your request, (1) the categories of Personally Identifiable Information we collect and what third parties we share that information with; (2) the names and addresses of those third parties; and (3) examples of the products marketed by those companies. The Act further requires us to allow you to control who you do not want us to share that information with. To obtain this information, please send a request by email _support@Ronharris.com_. . When contacting us, please indicate your name, address, email address, and what Personally Identifiable Information you do not want us to share with Affiliated Businesses or Marketing Partners. The request should be sent to the attention of our legal department, and labeled "California Customer Choice Notice." Please allow 30 days for a response. Also, please note that there is no charge for controlling the sharing of your Personally Identifiable Information or requesting this notice. ****

**Contacting Us**

If you have questions or concerns about our Privacy Policy, please contact us at: _support@Ronharris.com_. Put the words "Privacy Policy" in the subject line.
